Congregation Tikvoh Chadoshoh Collection 0011.001.003a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
Tikvoh Chadoshoh, Congregation
1942-2000s
0011.001.003a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
1.0 Cubic feet 2 Boxes
In 1942 Rabbi Hans Bodenheimer and other German Holocaust survivors founded Congregation Tikvoh Chadoshoh "New Hope" in Hartford. After meeting in borrowed space for many years, the Congregation's first building was dedicated in 1956. In 1971, following a series of anti-Semitic acts in Hartford, the congregation built a new synagogue in Bloomfield. Rabbi Bodenheimer served as spiritual leader of the Congregation until his retirement
Photos
See Miscellaneous Synagogue photographs for phot images related to Tikvoh Chadoshoh.
Scope and Contents note
This is a small collection consisting of minutes from the 1960s through 1980s, scrapbooks and a handful of other materials. Several scrapbooks, compiled and donated by Gloria Bein are included. Due to serious deterioration, these scrapbooks have been photocopied onto plain paper.
Box 1: A-R
Anniversaries/20th, 1961
Anniversaries/25th, 1966
Anniversaries/35th, 1977
Anniversaries/40th, 1981
Anniversaries/45th, 1987
Anniversaries/50th, 1992
Awards/Jewish Writing Awards for children
Board of directors/Members
Board of Directors/Minutes, 1960s
Board of Directors/Minutes, 1970s
Board of Directors/Minutes, 1970s-1980s
Board of Directors/Minutes, 1980s-1990s
Buildings/25 Cornwall Street, 1956
Buildings/18 Still Road, 1971
Education/Graduations and Confirmations
Education/ School Activities
Fundraising
Historical Highlights
Holocaust Commemorations, 1940s-2000s
Holocaust Commemorations/Kristallnacht
Members and Membership
Music, Choir, and Cantorial Programs
New Americans/Soviet Jews,
Newsletters
Newspaper clippings
Miscellaneous
Rabbis
Rabbis/Bodenheimer see also Bodenheimer Collection
Rabbis/Fish, Joseph M. "Ron"
Rabbis/Kaplan, Larry G.
Ritual Matters and Shabbat Events
Box 2: S-Z
1.Scrapbook, 1930s-1980s
2.Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s
3.Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s
4. Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s
Sisterhood
Related Archival Materials note
There is some overlap between the contents of the Congregation Tikvoh Chadoshoh and Bodenheimer Collections. Researchers should consult both collections.
- Series II: Tikvoh Chadoshoh Records & Manuscripts,: S-Z
  - Scrapbook, 1930s-1980s, 1930-1989 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 2)
  - Sisterhood, undated (Box 2)
- Series I: Tikvoh Chadoshoh Records & Manuscripts, A-R
  - Anniversaries/20th, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries/25th, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries/35th, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries/40th, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries/45th, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries/50th, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Awards/Jewish Writing Awards for children, undated (Box 1)
  - Board of directors/Members, undated (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1970s-1980s, 1970-1989 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors/Minutes, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 1)
  - Buildings/25 Cornwall Street, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Buildings/18 Still Road, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Education/Graduations and Confirmations, undated (Box 1)
  - Education/ School Activities, undated (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 1)
  - Historical Highlights, undated (Box 1)
  - Holocaust Commemorations, 1940s-2000s, 1940-2000 (Box 1)
  - Holocaust Commemorations/Kristallnacht, undated (Box 1)
  - Members and Membership, undated (Box 1)
  - Music, Choir, and Cantorial Programs, undated (Box 1)
  - New Americans/Soviet Jews, undated (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1)
  - Rabbis, undated (Box 1)
  - Rabbis/Bodenheimer see also Bodenheimer Collection, undated (Box 1)
  - Rabbis/Fish, Joseph M. "Ron", undated (Box 1)
  - Rabbis/Kaplan, Larry G., undated (Box 1)
  - Ritual Matters and Shabbat Events, undated (Box 1)